Like I said Normally, this definitely isn't going to be the way that you're going to write your smart contracts,
就像我说过的，通常来说，这并不是你编写智能合约该用的方式
it's almost impossible to write a full smart contract without making any mistakes. And without flipping back and forth between documentation,
你几乎不太可能在不参考文档而且不犯任何错误的前提下直接写完一份完整的智能合约
I have already written this contract many times myself, and I still made a whole bunch of mistakes.
我自己已经多次编写过这个合约了，然而我仍然会犯很多错误
So it is totally reasonable and totally rational for anybody and everybody to make mistakes going through this.
所以对任何人来说，在这个过程中出错都是完全可以理解的
And to use resources and to write tests along the way.
同样的，在这个过程中参考资源，编写测试也是很合理的
Now that we have our raffle dot Seoul created,
现在我们已经把 "Raffle.sol" 写完了
it's time to add everything else.
是时候添加其他内容了
So we're going to come over here, we're gonna create a new folder, and add our deploy folder per usual.
所以我们来到这边，新建一个文件夹，也就是我们通常会添加的 "deploy" 文件夹
And we're going to do exactly what we've already done a couple of times,
而且做法就和我们之前几次完全一样
we're going to create some scripts to deploy our raffle contract.
我们要创建一些脚本来部署我们的 "Raffle" 合约
Now with our raffle contract, there's a couple of things in here that we want to make note of
现在，关于我们的 "Raffle" 合约，有几点需要注意的地方
first thing is that our constructor right now is absolutely massive.
首先是，我们的构造函数现在真的是挺大的了
There are a ton of parameters in here that we need to account for.
这里有许多参数需要我们去考虑
Let's take a look at our constructors and see if there's any contracts that we're already interacting with.
让我们来看一下我们的构造函数，看看是否有我们已经正在交互的合约
Okay, VRF, coordinator v2. This is a contract address,
OK，"VRFCoordinatorV2"，这是一个合约地址
entrance fee, no gasline, no subscription ID no callback, guestimate No, and interval. No.
"entranceFee" 不是，"gasLane" 不是，"subscriptionId" 不是，"callbackGasLimit" 不是，以及 "interval" 也不是
So knowing that this is an address should be a tip that Ah,
那么，知道这是一个地址也就意味着有这么一个提示
okay, we're probably going to need to deploy some mocks. For this,
啊，我们很可能需要为它部署一些 "mock"
since we're going to need to interact with a VRF coordinator contract that's outside of our project.
因为我们要交互的 "vrfCoordinator" 合约来自于我们的外部项目
But let's go ahead and start working on our raffle deployment script
现在让我们开始编写我们的 "Raffle" 部署脚本
first, and we know we're going to have to deploy some mocks. So we'll just keep that in mind.
首先我们知道要部署一些 "mock"，我们要记住这一点
So let's create a new file. Oh, one, deploy raffle.js.
所以让我们创建一个新的文件 `01-deploy-raffle.js`
And let's get started deploying our raffle contract.
然后让我们开始部署我们的 "Raffle" 合约
Now, this is going to look really similar to what we've done before. And we're going to do it again here.
就和我们之前做的非常类似，我们会在这里再做一遍
If you want to use your previous deploy scripts as a reference, I absolutely recommend you do so.
如果你想的话，我也非常建议你参考你之前写的部署脚本
But let's get started with module that exports equals an async function.
让我们从这里开始 `module.exports = async function()`
That's going to take get named accounts and deployments. As input parameters,
它接收 `getNamedAccounts, deployments` 作为输入参数
then we're going to do const. Deploy log equals deployments,
然后是 `const  = deployments`
then we're gonna say const, Deployer, equals await, get named accounts.
再然后是 `const  = await getNamedAccounts`
Let's go to our config and update module that exports to to have this
前往我们的 "config" 文件，更新 "module.exports" 为这个样子
I'm just going to copy paste, so that employer is going to be defaulted to account zero and player is going to be defaulted to account one,
我直接复制粘贴了，所以 "deployer" 默认为账户 0，"player" 默认为账户 1
if you want to go ahead and write this out, feel free to pause and write out your name accounts. Right now,
如果你想自己写，可以现在暂停下来，并写下你的账户名
there's gonna be a lot of boilerplate in our heart hat.config.js.
在我们的 "hardhat.config.js" 中有很多样板代码
So feel free to have the GitHub repo for this lesson up with you or your previous scripts that you've already written as a reference
所以请自由参考本课程的 GitHub 仓库或是你以前编写的脚本
named accounts Deployer. And we're also going to have a player named account
"namedAccounts", "deployer" 并且在 "namedAccounts" 还有一个 "player"
so that we can separate different users or different players who are interacting with our contracts.
这样我们就可以区分与我们的合约进行交互的不同用户
But for now, we're gonna grab our Deployer. And we're gonna get started.
现在，我们获取了 "deployer"，让我们开始吧
Now similar to last time, we would just do const, raffle equals await ploy, raffle, comma,
就和上次一样，我们要做的就是 `const raffle = await deploy("Raffle", {})`
and then add all of our stuff in here, right?
然后就是添加我们所需的所有内容，对吧？
So this would be from Deployer.
这里是 `from: deployer`
args, we're going to have a ton of args. So we're going to come back to this.
`args`，我们会有很多 "args" 所以我们之后再回来写
And then log is going to be true.
然后是 `log: true`
And then we're going to have wait confirmations,
再然后是 `waitConfirmations`
there's a little bit more boilerplate we need to work with here
这里我们还需要使用更多的样板代码
in our Hardhead config, we don't have a network here.
我们的 "hardhat.config" 这里还没有 "network"
So let's add our network information. So we can get those block confirmations
所以我们来添加一下 "network" 信息，这样我们就可以获取到他们的区块确认数了
will be specific in here, as well. And we'll say default network is going to be hard hat.
我们在这里指定一下 `defaultNetwork: "hardhat"`
And then we'll say networks, and we'll add our network information
接下来是 `networks`，然后添加我们的 "network" 信息
that's going to be working with heart hub,
我们用的就是 "hardhat"
which has a chain ID of 31337 miles, we'll put that in here as well.
它的 `chainId` 是 `31337`，放在这里
And block confirmations were just set to one
`blockConfirmations` 直接设置为 1
lot this column here,
这里少了个逗号
we're also gonna be running some staging tests on the Rinkeby network.
同时，我们的 "staging" 测试会运行于 `rinkeby` 网络
So we'll add rink B in here with a chain ID of four, block confirmations of six,
所以我们这里添加 "rinkeby"，以及 `chainId: 4` 以及 `blockConfirmations: 6`
and we need to add a URL and then also some accounts
此外我们还需要一个 `url` 以及一些 `accounts`
for our URL. We've done this 100 times.
"url" 我们已经处理过很多次了
We'll do const. rinky dink could be RPC URL equals process study and v dot rake, the RPC URL,
`const RINKEBY_RPC_URL = process.env.RINKEBY_RPC_URL`
that's private key, blah, blah, blah,
还有 "PRIVATE_KEY" 之类的 blah blah blah
we're going to add all these same variables from our last projects.
我们直接从我们上一个项目的变量中添加
So I'm going to ask you to pause here and just copy paste all those variables from our last project.
所以你这里需要暂停一下，然后直接复制粘贴上一个项目中的变量
Boom, like so
嘭，就像这样
since running rink, prpc, URL, private key corn market cap and ether scan,
由于这里用到了 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL", "PRIVATE_KEY", "COINMARKETCAP" 以及 "ETHERSCAN"
we're also going to want to make sure you folder, excuse me, new file, dot env.
所以我们当然需要一个新的文件夹，抱歉，一个新的文件 `.env`
And we're going to drop all of our information in here
然后把我们的所有信息都放进去
our rink, prpc, URL, private key, ether scan API key, and then our coin market cap API key as well.
包括 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL", "PRIVATE_KEY", "ETHERSCAN_API_KEY" 以及我们的 "COINMARKETCAP_API_KEY"
Now that we have our private key or ring prpc URL down in URL,
现在我们有了 "PRIVATE_KEY" 以及 "RINKEBY_RPC_URL"，往下拉到 "url" 这里
B RPC URL, and for accounts, we're just going to add that single private key.
添加 `RINKEBY_RPC_URL`，以及 "accounts" 添加一个单独的 "PRIVATE_KEY"
Now for weight confirmations is going to equal For network config dot block con formations, or one,
现在对于我们 "waitConfirmations" 它等于 `network.config.blockConfirmations || 1`
we're gonna have to import network from Hardhead,
我们还要从 "hardhat" 中导入 "network"
which looks like my VS code automatically did for me. Thanks VS code.
看起来这是我的 VS Code 自动帮我做的，谢谢你 VS Code
So this is how we're going to deploy a raffle.
这就是我们部署 "Raffle" 的方法
Obviously, we have a ton of arguments that we need to account for.
当然，我们还需要为账户添加很多参数
So let's get to it.
让我们来处理一下
Let's look at our raffle constructor to see what we need to get.
我们来查看一下我们的 "Raffle" 构造函数，看看我们都需要获取些什么
Okay, well, the first thing that we need to get via of coordinator v2,
首先我们需要获取的是 "vrfCoordinatorV2"
we're gonna use the same strategy we used in our Funmi project
我们会采用与 "FundMe" 项目中相同的策略
with using mocks, if we're on a development chain,
也就是使用 "mock"，如果是在开发链上的话
and using the actual contract address if we're on a test net, or a live network,
然后在测试网或者真实网络中再使用实际的合约地址
so let's get to it.
让我们开始吧
So let's go ahead, recreate that helper, hard hat config dot j s
重建 "helper-hardhat-config.js"
and create that const. Network. Config, say it equals
然后创建 `const networkConfig =`
for hard hat, we're going to use a mock.
对于 "hardhat" 来说，我们要使用一个 "mock"
So we don't need to put that in here for now.
所以我们暂时不需要填入任何内容
But for rink B, let's go ahead, but a foreign here,
但对于 rinkeby，这里是 4
so the name is going to be Rinkeby.
`name` 是 `"rinkeby"`
And we're going to need to go to the chain link documentation, the VRF contracts,
接下来我们需要前往 "Chainlink" 文档中的 "vrf-contracts"
and we're going to need to grab the RF coordinator for the Rinkeby. Test net,
然后获取 "Rinkeby" 测试网的 "vrfCoordinator"
we're going to grab this address here,
我们获取这里的地址
plop it in here, we'll say V RF core did an eight tour v two, bam, right like that.
把它放在这里 `vrfCoordinatorV2` 粘贴，就像这样
So back in our deploy raffle, we're gonna have to pick whether or not to use the V RF coordinator v two in the network config or some mock that we deployed,
回到我们的 "deploy-raffle"，我们要决定是使用 "networkConfig" 中的 "vrfCoordinatorV2" 还是部署一些 "mock" 来使用
which of course, leads us to us having to deploy a mock,
当然了，我们还必须要部署一个 "mock"
let's create the new file 00. Deploy marks.js.
让我们创建一个新的文件 `00-deploy-mocks.js`
So same thing module that exports equals async function
还是一样的操作 `module.exports = async function()`
where it's taking, get named accounts, and deployments, as its input variables from the heart at runtime environment,
它接收 `getNamedAccounts, deployments` 作为输入变量，来源于 hardhat 运行环境
or do const deploy COMM A log equals deployments.
然后是 `const  = deployments`
And then const, Deployer equals await, get named accounts, Excel,
再然后是 `const  = await getNamedAccounts()`，就是这样
and then we're going to grab the chain ID as well as we're going to only wants to deploy this on a development chain.
接下来我们要获取 "chainId" 因为我们只想把这个部署到开发链上
So we'll do const chain ID equals network dot config dot chain ID.
所以我们要运行 `const chainId = network.config.chainId`
（实际上应为 `network.name`）
Now we're going to only want to deploy mocks, if we're on a development chain.
现在，我们只想在开发链上部署 "mock"
So once again, we're going to go to our helper config, we're going to add those development chains in here.
所以我们再一次来到 "helper-config"，把开发链添加到这里来
We'll say const, development chains equals hard hat, and localhost.
`const developmentChains = ["hardhat", "localhost"]`
And then we're gonna want to export both
接下来我们要把它们都导出出来
So module, dot exports, equals network config, and development chance.
所以就是 `module.exports = `
Now in our deploy mocks, we're gonna want to grab those
现在来到我们的 "deploy-mocks"，我们要把它们都获取过来
are saying const development chains, equals require dot dot slash helper helper hardhat config.
`const  = require("../helper-hardhat-config")`
Now we can check to see if development chains dot includes the network dot name that we're currently on.
现在，我们开始检查 `if(developmentChains.includes(network.name))` 也就是我们当前所在网络名
If we're in a development chain, we're gonna go ahead and log local network, the protected, deploying box.
如果我们在开发链上，就执行 `log("Local network detected! Deploying mocks...")`
And now we'll have to deploy a mock VRF coordinator,
我们要部署一个模拟的 "vrfcoordinator"
where do we get a mock VRF to coordinator
所以我们要先获取一个模拟的 "vrfcoordinator"
Well, let's go ahead and create one of those.
好的，让我们继续，创建一个出来